<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Control theory on </title>
    <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/categories/control-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Control theory on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://phatcvo.github.io/categories/control-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Model Predictive Control with discrete-time Control Barrier Functions</title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/model-predictive-control-with-discrete-time-control-barrier-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/model-predictive-control-with-discrete-time-control-barrier-functions/</guid>
      <description>The MPC-CBF optimization problem is given by:
$$\begin{aligned} \min_{u_{t: t+N-1 \mid t}} \quad &amp;amp; \frac{1}{2} \tilde{x}_N^T Q_x \tilde{x}_N+\sum_{k=0}^{N-1} \frac{1}{2} \tilde{x}_k^T Q_x \tilde{x}_k+\frac{1}{2} u_k^T Q_u u_k\\ \textrm{s.t.} \quad &amp;amp; x_{t+k+1 \mid t}=x_{t+k \mid t}+f\left(x_{t+k \mid t}, u_{t+k \mid t}\right) \cdot T_s, \quad k=0, . ., N-1,\\ &amp;amp; x_{\min } \leq x_{t+k \mid t} \leq x_{\max }, \quad k=0, \ldots, N-1,\\ &amp;amp; u_{\min } \leq u_{t+k \mid t} \leq u_{\max }, \quad k=0, \ldots, N-1, \\ &amp;amp; x_{t \mid t}=x_t, \\ &amp;amp; \Delta h\left(x_{t+k \mid t}, u_{t+k \mid t}\right) \geq-\gamma h\left(x_{t+k \mid t}\right), \quad k=0, \ldots, N-1 \\ \end{aligned}$$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-linear trajectory optimization via Differential Dynamic Programming with the iLQR/DDP algorithm</title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/iterative-linear-quadratic-regulator-and-differential-dynamic-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/iterative-linear-quadratic-regulator-and-differential-dynamic-programming/</guid>
      <description>Differential Dynamic Programming (DDP) is an indirect method which optimizes over the unconstrained control-space. It uses a 2nd-order Taylor series approximation of the cost-to-go in Dynamic Programming (DP) to compute Newton steps on the control trajectory.
iLQR: Only keeps the first-order terms (Gauss-Newton approximation), which is similar to Riccati iterations, but accounts for the regularization and line-search required to handle the nonlinearity. DDP: Second-order terms included (Newton approximation). The iLQR/DDP controller solves the following finite-horizon optimization (Non-linear trajectory optimization) problem:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nominal Nonlinear Model Predictive Control </title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/nominal-nonlinear-model-predictive-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/nominal-nonlinear-model-predictive-control/</guid>
      <description>Nonlinear model predictive control (NMPC) is a popular control method for multivariable control problems with important process constraints. The dynamic equation system is assumed to be given by differential algebraic equations (DAE). The code is mostly meant to be used as a way to verify the performance of more novel algorithms against an implementation more likely to be found in industry. It has the following features:
Cheap NMPC implementation for both receding and shrinking time horizons Parameter and state estimation using the UKF Efficient solution of nonlinear dynamic optimization formulation using automatic differentiation Always feasible due to soft-constraints Example This is a basic nonlinear model predictive control (NMPC) implementation in Python with soft constraints, which uses an Unscented Kalman filter for state estimation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Model Predictive Control</title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/linear-model-predictive-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/linear-model-predictive-control/</guid>
      <description>Vehicle model linearization Vehicle model is
$$ \dot{x} = vcos(\phi)$$
$$ \dot{y} = vsin((\phi)$$
$$ \dot{v} = a$$
$$ \dot{\phi} = \frac{vtan(\delta)}{L}$$
State and Input vector:
$$ z = \begin{bmatrix} x-position \\\ y-position \\\ velocity \\\ yaw-angle\end{bmatrix} = \begin{bmatrix} x \\\ y \\\ v \\\ \phi\end{bmatrix} $$
$$u = \begin{bmatrix} acceleration \\ steering-angle \end{bmatrix} = \begin{bmatrix} a \\ \delta \end{bmatrix} $$
ODE is
$$ \dot{z} =\frac{\partial }{\partial z} z = f(z, u) = A&amp;rsquo;z+B&amp;rsquo;u$$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe-Optimal Control for Motional Planning based on RL</title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/safe-optimal-control-for-motional-planning-based-on-rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/safe-optimal-control-for-motional-planning-based-on-rl/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents Optimal Control Dynamic Programming Linear Programming Tree-Based Planning Control Theory Model Predictive Control Safe Control Robust Control Risk-Averse Control Value-Constrained Control State-Constrained Control and Stability Uncertain Dynamical Systems Game Theory Sequential Learning Multi-Armed Bandit Best Arm Identification Black-box Optimization Reinforcement Learning Theory Value-based Policy-based Policy Gradient Actor-critic Derivative-free Model-based Exploration Hierarchy and Temporal Abstraction Partial Observability Transfer Multi-agent Representation Learning Offline Learning from Demonstrations Imitation Learning Applications to Autonomous Driving Inverse Reinforcement Learning Applications to Autonomous Driving Motion Planning Search Sampling Optimization Reactive Architecture and applications Optimal Control: Dynamic Programming (book) Dynamic Programming, Bellman R.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
