<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Blog on </title>
    <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Blog on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nominal Nonlinear Model Predictive Control </title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/nominal-nonlinear-model-predictive-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/nominal-nonlinear-model-predictive-control/</guid>
      <description>Nonlinear model predictive control (NMPC) is a popular control method for multivariable control problems with important process constraints. The dynamic equation system is assumed to be given by differential algebraic equations (DAE). The code is mostly meant to be used as a way to verify the performance of more novel algorithms against an implementation more likely to be found in industry. It has the following features:
Cheap NMPC implementation for both receding and shrinking time horizons Parameter and state estimation using the UKF Efficient solution of nonlinear dynamic optimization formulation using automatic differentiation Always feasible due to soft-constraints Example [1][2] Simulation, which should run the pre-defined problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Model Predictive Control</title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/linear-model-predictive-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/linear-model-predictive-control/</guid>
      <description>Vehicle model linearization Vehicle model is
$$ \dot{x} = vcos(\phi)$$
$$ \dot{y} = vsin((\phi)$$
$$ \dot{v} = a$$
$$ \dot{\phi} = \frac{vtan(\delta)}{L}$$
State and Input vector:
$$ z = \begin{bmatrix} x-position \\\ y-position \\\ velocity \\\ yaw-angle\end{bmatrix} = \begin{bmatrix} x \\\ y \\\ v \\\ \phi\end{bmatrix} $$
$$u = \begin{bmatrix} acceleration \\ steering-angle \end{bmatrix} = \begin{bmatrix} a \\ \delta \end{bmatrix} $$
ODE is
$$ \dot{z} =\frac{\partial }{\partial z} z = f(z, u) = A&amp;rsquo;z+B&amp;rsquo;u$$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe-Optimal Control for Motional Planning based on RL</title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/safe-optimal-control-for-motional-planning-based-on-rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/safe-optimal-control-for-motional-planning-based-on-rl/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents Optimal Control Dynamic Programming Linear Programming Tree-Based Planning Control Theory Model Predictive Control Safe Control Robust Control Risk-Averse Control Value-Constrained Control State-Constrained Control and Stability Uncertain Dynamical Systems Game Theory Sequential Learning Multi-Armed Bandit Best Arm Identification Black-box Optimization Reinforcement Learning Theory Value-based Policy-based Policy Gradient Actor-critic Derivative-free Model-based Exploration Hierarchy and Temporal Abstraction Partial Observability Transfer Multi-agent Representation Learning Offline Learning from Demonstrations Imitation Learning Applications to Autonomous Driving Inverse Reinforcement Learning Applications to Autonomous Driving Motion Planning Search Sampling Optimization Reactive Architecture and applications Optimal Control: Dynamic Programming (book) Dynamic Programming, Bellman R.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory of Motion Planning</title>
      <link>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/trajectories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://phatcvo.github.io/blog/trajectories/</guid>
      <description>Motion Planning There are a few more essential skills that we need in our toolbox. In this chapter, we will explore some of the powerful methods of kinematic trajectory motion planning.
I&amp;rsquo;m actually almost proud of making it this far into the notes without covering this topic yet. Writing a relatively simple script for the pose of the gripper, like we did in the bin picking chapter, really can solve a lot of interesting problems.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
